Meng-Jiun Chiou

(邱盟竣)

Taipei, Taiwan

coldmanck@gmail.com http://coldmanck.github.io https://www.linkedin.com/in/coldmanck

SUMMARY

I am an ambitious student embracing computer science, mainly on computer vision (CV), machine learning (ML) and multimedia processing. I love to learn new techniques and implement great ideas coming up to my mind. Up to now, I have been working on not only a variety of research projects related to computer vision but also countless interesting in-class projects with multiple programming languages, e.g. C, C++, Java, Python and MATLAB.

SKILLS

Java

• C, C++

Matlab

- · Python
- Computer Vision
- · Social Skills
- · Chinese
- English

· Japanese

· Taiwanese

EXPERIENCE

Academia Sinica

12 / 2015 - 04 / 2016

Research Assistant (RA)

I had been conducting research concerning to image segmentation at Multimedia and Machine Learning (MML) LAB, Academia Sinica.

Microsoft Taiwan

07 / 2013 - 06 / 2014

R&D Groups, Microsoft Student Partners (MSPs)

During my internship, I developed several Windows Apps (for instance, NHK Reader which was available in Sep. 2013 has 7,000+ downloads so far) and made speech for students to help people being more familiar with Microsoft techniques and services.

EDUCATION

National Chiao Tung University (NCTU)

09 / 2012 - 06 / 2016

Bachelor of Science (BS), Electrical and Computer Engineering

- · Vice President, Chien-Kuo and Taipei First Girls' High School Alumni Association
- · Member, NCTU Photography Club

The University of Tokyo (UTokyo)

10/2014 - 09/2015

Exchange Student, Information and Communication Engineering

- · Research Student, Aizawa-Yamasaki Lab (Multimedia Processing Lab)
- · Member, UTokyo Photography Club

PUBLICATIONS A Fast Method of Visual Words Assignment of Bag-of-Features for Object 07 / 2015 Recognition

M.-J. Chiou, Y. Toshihiko and K. Aizawa (The University of Tokyo)

Extended Abstract Paper with Poster Presentation, in The 18th Meeting on Image Recognition and Understanding, Jul. 2015. Source code has been released on GitHub: https://github.com/coldmanck/A-Fast-Method-of-Visual-Words-Assignment-of-Bag-of-Features-for-Object-Recognition

A Fast Table-Based Approach of Bag-of-Features for Large-Scale Image Classification 08 / 2015

M.-J. Chiou, Y. Toshihiko and K. Aizawa (The University of Tokyo)

Short Paper with Oral Presentation, in *ITE (The Institute of Image Information and Television Engineers) Annual Convention*, Aug. 2015.

CERTIFICATIONS

TOEFL®	iBT	Test -	92	points	
TC 1 - 41	1.70		•	(ETC)	

05 / 2016

Educational Testing Service (ETS)

TOEIC[®] **Test – 810 points**

09 / 2014

Educational Testing Service (ETS)

Japanese Language Proficiency Test (JLPT) - Level N1

07 / 2013

The Japan Foundation

AWARDS

JASSO Student Exchange Support Program Scholarship

10 / 2014

Japan Student Services Organization (JASSO)

NCTU Short-Term Exchange Scholarship

10 / 2014

Office of International Affairs, NCTU

Xiao Yuan-Long Scholarship

05 / 2014

Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, NCTU

Award for Excellence

04 / 2014

The 8th SUMIKA Cup Japanese Speech Contest, SUMIKA Technology co., ltd.

LANGUAGES

Chinese

(Native proficiency)

Japanese English (Full professional proficiency)(Professional working proficiency)

EXTRACURRICU

Vice President

LAR ACTIVITIES

Chien-Kuo and Taipei First Girls' High School Alumni Association NCTU

In NCTU, I had been a vice president of "Chien-Kuo and Taipei First Girls' High School Alumni Association" for one academic year. I took on leadership roles by organizing a variety of events.

INTERESTS

Table tennis, jogging, digital photography, novel and Japanese TV program